Guide to the Edward Lee Plumb Papers, 1856-1912
Department of Special Collections
- CORRESPONDENCE 1898, January - March (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 16. Feb. 26.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 17. & 18. Feb. 28.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S. & copy.
  - 19. Mar. 4.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 20. Mar. 8.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. Mar. 10.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. Mar. 12.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., Tel.
  - 23. Mar. 13.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Maine incident., A.L.S.
  - 24. Mar. 16.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 25. Mar. 17.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 26. Mar. 18.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 27. Mar. 19.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 28. Mar. 20.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. Mar. 21.E.L.P. to R.R. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 30. Mar. 23.Chas. P. Daly to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. Mar. 24.M. Romero to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 32. Mar. 24.E.L.P. to Wayne MacVeagh., A.L.S.
  - 33. Mar. 25.Henry Cabot Lodge to E.L.P., T.L.S. & franked cvr.
  - 34. Mar. 26.E.L.P. to R.P. Hitt., A.L.S.
  - 35. Mar. 27.Wayne MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 36. Mar. 28.E.L.P. to Redfield Proctor., A.L.S.
  - 37. Mar. 29.H.C. Lodge to E.L.P., T.N.S. & franked cvr.
  - 38. Mar. 29.E.L.P. to unknown., A.L.S. & encls.
  - 39. Mar. 30.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1898, April - July 17 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 1. Apr. 2.Geo. C. Hurlbut to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 2. Apr. 15.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 3. Apr. 17.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 4. Apr. 22.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. War with Spain., A.L.S.
  - 5. Apr. 22.Giovanni Pelleschi to E.L.P., A.L.S. [in Sp.?].
  - 6. Apr. 29.M. Romero to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 7. Apr. 30.Mrs. Allen Romero to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. May 17.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 9. May 17.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 10. May 24.Galusha A. Grow to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. May 27.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. [May 27][Alice Chri-----] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. June 15.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.
  - 14. June 17.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 15. [June 20]Chas. Paul Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. June 23.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 17. June 25.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 18. June 27.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 19. July 1.Geo. T. [?] to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. July 2.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 21. July 5.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. July 6.E.L.P. to [William R.] Day., A.L.S.
  - 23. July 7.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 24. July 8.Elizabeth T. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. July 9.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day. Extract from paper by W.R. Shafter., A.L.S. & extract.
  - 26. July 13.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 27. July 16.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 28. July 17.E.L.P. to William R. Day., A.N.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1898, July 18 - December. (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - 1. July 18.William R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 2. July 18.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 3. July 19.Wm. R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 4. July 20.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.N.S.
  - 5. July 21.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day. Puerto Rico, Cuba, Sp. prisoners., A.L.S.
  - 6. July 23.E.L.P. to Wm. R. Day., A.L.S.
  - 7. July 26.Wm. R. Day to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 8. July 29.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 9. July 29.M. Romero to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. Aug. 15.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 11. Sep. 21.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. Sep. 23.Jas. Steuart Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. [1898, Sep.]., Note.
  - 14. Oct. 11.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Oct. 21.Sarah N. Knight to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. [Oct. 25].Chas. Paul Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. Nov. 5.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. & 19. Nov. 11.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., 2 A.L.S. & clip.
  - 20. Nov. 17.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. Nov. 22.E.L.P. to Geo. E. Church., A.L.S.
  - 22. Nov. 23.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. Nov. 23.Sarah N. Knight to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 24. Dec. 8.M. Romero to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 25. [Dec. 9].S.A. Newton to E.L.P., Card.
  - 26. Dec. 10.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 27. Dec. 22.L.M. Johnson to E.L.P., T.N.S.
  - 28. [Dec. 26].Elizabeth McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. Dec. 31.E.L.P. to L.M. Johnson. Death of Romero., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1899 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - 1. Jan. 7.Addison Mitchell to E.L.P., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 2. Jan. 15.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Phillipines., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 3. Jan. 23.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 4. Jan. 24.Mary Parke Foster to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 5. Jan. 26.E.L.P. to Mary Parke Foster, A.L.S.
  - 6. Feb. 5.E.L.P. to Galusha A. Grow., A.L.S.
  - 7. Feb. 7.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Treaty with Spain., A.L.S.
  - 8. Feb. 8.E.L.P. to W.J. Sewell., A.L.S.
  - 9. Feb. 9.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 10. Feb. 9.E.L.P. to Galusha A. Grow., A.L.S.
  - 11. Feb. 18.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P. Mentions Shafter, asks where he plans to archive his material-Maximilian's invasion of Mexico., A.L.S.
  - 12. Mar. 4.W.J. Sewell to E.L.P., T.L.S. & franked cvr.
  - 13. Mar. 15.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. Mar. 21.James S. Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. Apr. 7.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. May 2.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. May 14.Elizabeth T. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. May 21.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. May 29.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 20. [June 6].Elizabeth T. McCormick to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. June 21.F. Walter Callender to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. June 23.Sarah N. Knight to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. July 7.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., L.S.
  - 24. Aug. 22.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. Sep. 1.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. Sep. 25.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 27. Nov. 3.Anna Roockwell to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 28. Nov. 16.E.L.P. to John W. Foster., A.L.S.
  - 29. Nov. 17.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 30. Nov. 18.E.L.P. to John W. Foster. Alaska boundary line., A.L.S.
  - 31. Nov. 22.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 32. Dec. 9.R.C. McCormick to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 33. Dec. 19.John W. Foster to E.L.P., A.L.S.
- CORRESPONDENCE 1902 - 1912 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 1. 1902, Feb. 13.Wayne MacVeagh to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 2. 1902, Feb. 14.E.L.P. to Wayne MacVeagh. Some biographical, give Phillipines to Japan., A.L.S.
  - 3. 1903, July 16.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P. Panama Canal., A.L.S.
  - 4. 1903, Sep. 5.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P. Panama Canal, Colombia, Casey, etc., A.L.S.
  - 5. 1903, Sep. 8.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S. & franked cvr.
  - 6. 1903, Sep. 9.E.L.P. to [Jno. T. Morgan]., A.L.S.
  - 7. 1903, Sep. 13.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 8. 1903, Sep. 14.E.L.P. to Jno. T. Morgan., A.L.S.
  - 9. 1904, May 5.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 10. 1904, May 6.E.L.P. to Jno. T. Morgan., A.L.S.
  - 11. 1904, May 17.Jno. T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 12. 1904, July 23.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 13. 1904, Aug. 13.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 14. 1904, Sep. 9.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 15. 1904, Sep. 15.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 16. 1904, Sep. 29.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 17. 1904, Oct. 6.J.T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 18. 1904, Oct. 26.J.T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 19. 1905, Apr. 21.J.T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 20. 1905, July 26.J.T. Morgan to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 21. 1906, Feb. 22.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 22. 1906, Apr. 14.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 23. 1906, July 26.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 24. 1906, Dec. 11.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 25. 1906, Dec. 27.G.E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 26. 1907, Jan. 10.[E.L.P.] on verse - request from Church., Note.
  - 27. 1907, Jan. 20.Geo. E. Church to E.L.P., A.L.S. & clip.
  - 28. 1908, July 7.Jas. Steuart Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 29. 1908, July 8.E.L.P. to Jas. Steuart Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 30. 1908, July 9.Jas. Steuart Mackie to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 31. 1908, July 16.Jas. Steuart Mackie to E.L.P., T.L.S.
  - 32. 1908, July 24.E.L.P. to Jas. Steuart Mackie., A.L.S.
  - 33. 1909, Aug. 9.[Wayne MacVeagh?] to E.L.P., A.N.S. & copy.
  - 34. 1909, Aug. 12.Editors of?, L. (copy).
  - 35. 1909, Aug. 13.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 36. 1909, Aug. 14.Wayne MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 37. 1909, Aug. 16.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 38. 1909, Aug. 17.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 39. 1909, Aug. 20.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 40. 1909, Aug. 21.Wayne MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 41. 1909, Aug. 22.[E.L.P.] to Wayne MacVeagh with short reply., A.N.
  - 42. 1909, Aug. 25.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 43. 1909, Aug. 26.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.N.S.
  - 44. 1909, Aug. 27.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.N.S.
  - 45. 1909, Aug. 28.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh With copy of article Church and State., A.N.S.
  - 46. 1909, Aug. 30.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.N.
  - 47. 1909, Aug. 31.W. MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 48. 1909, Sep. 1.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 49. 1909, Oct. 4.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 50. 1909, Nov. 5.W. MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 51. 1910, July 21.J.O. Jones to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 52. 1910, July 30E.L.P. to J.O. Jones, A.L.S.
  - 53. 1910, Aug. 1.W. MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.L.S.
  - 54. 1910, Aug. 2.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.L.S.
  - 55. 1910, Aug. 29.E.L.P. to Wayne MacVeagh., A.N.S. & clip.
  - 56. 1910, Sep. 3.W. MacVeagh to E.L.P., A.N.S.
  - 57. 1910, Sep. 5.E.L.P. to W. MacVeagh, A.N.S.
  - 58. 1911, Nov. 14.W.H. Lowdermilk & Co. to E.L.P. With notes & bill., T.L.S.
  - 59. 1912, Feb. 5.E.L.P. to Thompson Publishing Co., A.N.S.
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS --1, (holograph) (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - 1. Encinillas Property. Chihuahua, Mexico. ca. 1865.Conveyance, etc., sketch, description and background.
  - 2. S. Lorenzo della Guanapa Property. Papantla Vera Cruz, Mexico. Notes on.
  - 3. Hacienda de San Lorenzo, San Blas, Jalisco, Mexico, Description. Barron, Forbes & Co.
  - 4. Railroad Contract in Mexico. Ca. 1874 - 1876.
  - 5. Pacific Railroad Surveys. Notes on line from San Antonio to E1 Paso.
  - 6. List of Treaties with Mexico. 1828 - 1861.
  - 7. Guarantee by the U.S. of the Neutrality of the Isthmus of Panama. Extracts.
  - 8. State Policy. [Df. of an article?]. de Lesseps & Panama canal project, U.S., Tehuantepee route, Mexico. The same entitled Our National Policy., 3 dup. pages.
  - 9. Mexico. Transit rights and the purchase of Lower California. Mr. Churchwell's Report. Condition of the country. Mexican debt held in England. 1859.With notes, copies and variations (see also folder 58).
  - 10. Notes on the relations of the United States to Slavery in Cuba. Relative commercial importance of the West Indies in the commerce of the U.S., for the year ending 30 June 1870. Extracts of letters. Imports of Sugar and Tobacco into U.S. from Cuba before and since insurrection commenced. Slave products introduced into the U.S. for year ending 30 June 1870, (two items), and the Revenue therefrom.
  - 11. Our Commerce with Central America. With clips. & statistics.
  - 12. Peru. Commercial statistics.
  - 13. Commercial statistics for Puerto Rico, Bolivia, Equador, Danish West Indies, French West Indies, French N. American Possessions, French Guiana, British West Indies, British Honduras, British Guiana, Dutch West Indies, Dutch Guiana, Hayti, Santo Domingo, Swedish West Indies. 1857 - 1876.
  - 14. Statement compiled from the English Parliamentary Reports showing the value of the commerce of the United Kingdom with Mexico, exclusive of spice. 1873 - 1877., 5 variations.
- MISCELLANEOUS PAPERS --2 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - 1. American Transit Routes - Their protection by U.S. Policy of this Government. Treaty stipulations now in force relating to the Tehuantepec route. The McLane-Ocampo Treaty. Instructions to U.S. Minister to Mexico. $10,000,000 offered for transit rights and cession of Lower California. Extracts of docs. and ltrs. (See also folder 57).
  - 2. Acquisitions of Territory by the U.S. Notes Regarding. Includes ptd. copy of 1795 treaty with Spain, notes, extracts, statistics, bibliographies, copies of letters and etc. by Plumb., clips
  - 3. Comments by the Duke of Wellington, on Spanish character
- RAILROAD PAPERS --1 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - 1. Texas & Pacific Railroad, Extracts, statistics, sketches, descriptions, reports., clips
  - 2. Galveston, Harrisburg and San Antonio Railroad.
- RAILROAD PAPERS --2 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - 1. Southern Pacific Railroad. Final copy.
  - 2. Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe Railroad.
- RAILROAD PAPERS --3 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - 1. Northern Pacific Railroad. Final copy of Report., Pp. 1 - 85.
  - 2. Pacific Railroad Material - surplus.
- BIOGRAPHICAL AND MISC. PTD. MATERIAL (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - 1. Typed biographical sketch, clip, holograph title of unfinished book.
  - 2. Cards: 1874International & Gt. Northern Railroad pass, 1898 & 1899passes & cvrs. Ferrocarril Internacional Mexicano; 3 National Geographic Society tickets 1897 - 1898;3 calling cards of E.L.P.; Metropolitan Museum of Art, 2 invitations & 2 admission tickets, 1897 - 1898.
  - 3. [1873, July 2].Sociedad Filarmonica Mexicana. R. Marie dela [Fore] and Jose M. Baranda., D.S. in Sp.
  - 4. 1872, Jan. 13.Sociedad Mexicana de Geografia y Estadistica. s. Ignacio Ramirez, Ignacio M. Altamirano & [Enfe----io] Miridore., D.S. in Sp.
  - 5. 1871, Nov. 28.La Compania Lancasteriana de Mexico. s. [W. ey] P. Gochicoa & Andres [Segutzamo]., D.S. in Sp.
  - 6. 1866, Feb. 12.L. William H. Seward to Marquis de Montholon. End of French invasion of Mexico, etc., Ptd. copy.
  - 7. Blank statistical form for Poor's Manual - Mexican International Railroad.
  - 8. 1872, Dec. 10.Balcarcel., Ptd. D. in Sp.
  - 9. 1872.Ferrocarril Internacional de Mexico., 2 brochures in Sp.
  - 10. 1865, Aug. 12.Steamers between Valparaiso & England., Ptd. decree.
  - 11. 1876, Dec.Express Mexicano export - import of Mexican goods., Brochure.
  - 12. 1865, Oct.Mexican Mining and Colonization Company., Statement & subscription form.
  - 13. 1851, Jan. 25.Convention between The United States of America and the Mexican Republic for the Protection of A Transit Way Across the Isthmus of Tehuantepec., Ptd. copy.
  - 14. An Important Aspect of the Mexican Question Based on the Comparative Financial Condition of the Country under Republican and Imperial Rule.
  - 15. Position and Prospects of the Mexican Pacific Company. 1858.E.L. Plumb's name appears Includes copy of charter. All printed.
- MAPS - (Primarily railroads in Mexico and Texas) (Box 6, Folder 63)
- PHOTOS AND CARTOONS (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - cartoons from Mexican sources in Sp. about the International Railroad, etc. - Plumb, Rosecrans, Barron, Lerdo de Tejada., 1 photo of E.L. Plumb
    [Other photos transferred to Special Collections' Photo Collection].
- CLIPPINGS (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Plumb's appointment to Mexico, 1867.Some general on Mexican situation.
  - Plumb's apptmt. to Havana. March and April 1869. (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 67)
    U.S. debt - bonds 1865; 1877 Transvall Annexation; Death of Gen. Rosecrans & George Baxter Newton, 1898; T. Roosevelt's letter to J.C. Martin, 1908.
  - U.S. and Costa Rica, 1905. (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - McLane - Ocampo Treaty, Treaty with Honduras, Cass - Igisarri Treaty with Nicaragua. (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - LaSere. Tehuantepee Concession. Oct. 6, 1867. (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Declaration of forfeiture of Concession to Catoree. (Box 6, Folder 71)
  - Mexico, etc. and in the U.S. 1878, 1876, 1879. (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - Cuban relations and Spanish - American War. (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Isthmus of Panama, Colombia, canal. (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Monroe Doctrine Resolutions. (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Steamship Lines - Contract on West Coast of Mexico, New York to Mexico, Pacific Mail SS contract & etc. (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Mexico, misc. (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - [Pennsylvania Railroad Co.]. Rosecrans vs. Plumb. (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Union & Central Pacific Consolidation. 1880, 1881. (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Atchison, Topeka & Santa Fe, North Pacific & other RR. 1879. (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Pacific Railroad - Commissioners' Exam., S.F. July - September 1887.Stanford, Huntington, etc. (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Southern Pacific Railroad & Extensions, 1881 - 1883.Some on Northern Pacific & others. (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Texas Railroad items and other material. ca. 1871. (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Austin to E1 Paso Charter, St. Louis, etc. ca. 1875 - 1877. (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - Vera Cruz Railroad. (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - International Railroad. December 12, 1874Contract. (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - International Railroad in Mexico. (Box 7, Folder 87)
  - Torreon, Mexico Railroad Station. (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - Mexican Southern Railroad, 1889. (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - Mexican Railroad dinner, 1880,etc. (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - Sonora Railroad Concession; Tehuantepec Railroad Concession. (Box 7, Folder 91)
  - Sonora Railroad Concession, 1877;Report of Com. on Vera Cruz RR tariffs; Coms. Mex. Congress, Fiscal statement; Celaya to Leon RR Concession; Vote on V.C. R.R. Tariff; Sullivan & Palmer RR Concession, 1877;etc.; Michoacan RR Concession. (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - Mexican Central Railroad, 1882 - 1884. (Box 8, Folder 93)
  - Mexican Central Railroad, 1883 - 1885. (Box 8, Folder 94)
  - Mexican Central Railroad, 1882 - 1889. (Box 8, Folder 95)
  - Railroad Project - San Luis Potosi to Tampico, 1875. (Box 8, Folder 96)
  - Blair - Sonora Railroad Concession; Matamores Railroad Concession; Esperon - Oaxaca; Tehuantepec Internation, 1873 - 1875. (Box 8, Folder 97)
  - Mexican and Railroad items, 1880 - 1881. (Box 8, Folder 98)
  - Misc. 1874, 1875.Mexico, commerce, RRs, mining, etc. (Box 8, Folder 99)
  - Misc. - Mexico. 1872, 1875, 1881 - 1883 & n.d. (Box 8, Folder 100)
  - Mexican Affairs Scrapbook, Vol. 1. 1857 - 1861Holograph notes & extracts, annotated by E.L.P., clips (Box 8, Volume 101 (vol.))
  - Mexican Affairs Scrapbook, Vol. 2. 1862 - 1863 (Volume 9 (vol.))
  - Index to Vol. 2. Mexican Affairs Scrapbook. (Volume 10 (vol.))
  - Mexican Affairs Scrapbook, Vol. 3. 1864, January - June. (Volume 11 (vol.))
  - Mexican Affairs Scrapbook, Vol. 4. 1864, July December. (Volume 12 (vol.))
  - Miscellaneous memorabilla - menu printed on cloth with Plumb's name in paint., one item - (Box 8, Folder 102)
PLUMB COLLECTION - PARTIAL INDEX
NOTE: The numbers indicate folders except where otherwise stated.
Alaska boundary line, 9 (acquisition), 48, 55.
Allen, George F. (pres., Mexican Pacific Coal, etc.), 1-3.
Allen, Thomas (1813-1882), 29, 30, 32, 36.
Altamirano, Ignacio Manuel (1834-1893), 20, 22, 62.
Alvarez, Juan (1790?-1867), 2 (mentioned).
Amazon River, 41-43.
Arbitration Treaty - 1897, 50.
Audenreid, Joseph Crain (d. 1880), 13, 15, 43.
Babcock, Orville E., 11-13, 16.
Badeau, Adam, 13, 17.
Balcárcel, Blas, 12, 23, 25-28, 34, 35, 62.
Ballon, George William, 44, 46.
Baranda, José M., 21, 62.
Baranda, P. de, 10, 11.
Barnes, John Sanford (pres., International RR), 29.
Barron, William or Guillermo (Barron, Forbes & Co.), 11, 64.
Barron, Forbes & Co., 25, 57.
Bates, Henry Walter, 42.
Belize see British Honduras.
Belknap, William Worth, 19.
Benecke, Esteban, 11, 12.
Berriozabal, Felipe B., 9.
Biddle, Thomas, 17.
Blake, William Phipps, 12, 31, 33, 34, 43-45.
Bond, Frank S., 34, 39.
Bond, William, 29, 32, 36.
Brackenridge, George W., 42.
Brazil, 41-43.
Bristed, Charles Astor, 20.
Bristed, Grace [S. or B.?], 17-19, 27.
British Honduras, 9, 50, 51, 57.
Brown, Charles Kearney, 13, 23.
Brown, [L.?] A., 24, 26, 27, 45.
Burnside, Ambrose Everett, 43.
Caballero y Fernandez de Rodas, Antonio, 15, 16 (copy).
Canada, 44.
Cañedo, Estanislao, 11, 12, 20, 21, 24, 28, 30, 32, 37, 41.
Castillo Velasco, José del, 19.
Chew, R. S., 13-15, 18, 19.
Chilton, R. S., 14, 16.
Church, George Earl, 8, 10, 15, 19-21, 24, 26, 28-31, 33-36, 38, 40-46, 49-56.
Church and state, 56.
Clarke, Hyde, 26-28, 30, 31, 43.
Coleman, William Tell, 15.
Colombia, 56, 74.
Commerce, 5, 18, 29, 39, 40, 42, 57.
Comonfort, Ignacio, 1 (mentioned), 2 (transl. of ltr.).
Corbiere, W. A., 6, 10.
Cornwell, Timothy, 2, 4.
Corwin, Thomas, 4.
Courcillon, E. de, 6.
Cowlitz Pass, Washington, 42.
Crawley, George B., 10, 20, 22.
Cross-Buchanan, William, 25, 34.
Cuba, 13-21, 25, 27, 28, 33, 36, 41-43, 48-54, 57.
Curran, Alexander L., 28.
Curtin, Andrew Gregg, 16.
Cushing, Caleb, 9, 10, 14, 15.
Daly, Charles Patrick, 50, 52.
Davidson, Nathaniel, 12, 19, 28.
Davis, Charles W., 10, 12.
Davis, John Chandler Bancroft, 10, 16 (copies), 19.
Day, William Rufus, 51-54.
Delano, Warren H., 33, 40.
Dewey, George, 45.
Diaz, Antonio C., 24, 25.
Diaz, Porfirio (José de la Cruz), mentioned only, 4, 19, 20, 33, 38.
Diaz, Ramon S., 10.
Dillon, John Forrest, 45.
Doubleday, Abner, 23.
Downey, Edward, 8, 9.
Dreyfus case, 52.
Dunbar, Edward E., 8, 9, 13.
Duncan, Alexander, 7.
Dwight, Theodore F., 44.
Enzenberg, Conde d', 21-24.
Escobedo, Mariano, 23, 39, 40, 41.
Evans, Walton W., 23-28.
Fergusson, D., 19.
Fesser, Francis, 12, 13.
Fesser, José Antonio, 17.
Fish, Hamilton, 15, 24, 32.
Flagg, John H., 42-44.
Forbin-Janson, _______, 14, 17.
Forney, John W., 17.
Forrest, George J., 30.
Foster, John Watson, 25-35, 42-44, 55.
Foster, William, 50.
French invasion of Mexico, 4, 6-9.
Gadsden, J. A., 12.
Garay, Francisco de, 22, 26.
Garrett, Thomas C., 1, 3.
Gates, J. E., 42.
Geiger, John L., 26-29, 31, 38.
Gerolt, F. von, 9-13.
Gibbs, C. C., 40, 41.
Gobright, L. A., 24.
Goodwin, John Noble, 19, 39, 42, 44.
Gorsuch, Robert B. (railroad promoter), 9.
Graham-Dunlop, A., 13, 14.
Granados, M. G., 25.
Grandison, Thomas, 22.
Grant, J. A., 44 (copies).
Grant, Ulysses Simpson, mentioned in - 5, 12, 16, 21, 22, 26, 35, 36, 44 (ltrs. to).
Grow, Galusha Aaron, 26, 53.
Guatamala, 9.
Gutiérrez, Luis, 12, 22.
Guzman, Ramon G., 11, 12, 21, 23-25.
Hall, Henry C., 14, 16-25, 28, 29, 33, 34, 36, 38-43, 45.
Hall, Robert L., 33.
Hanson, William R., 3.
Harris, Ira, 10.
Havana, Cuba, 13-16, 66.
Hayes, R. S., 31, 33-35, 38, 42, 44.
Hayes, Rutherford Birchard, mentioned in - 38.
Herrereo de Tejada, Feliciano, 19.
Hill, John, 24, 28.
Hoadley, David, 11, 13, 23.
Hoff, Henry K., 14, 15, 19.
Hogan, George W., 10.
Hoxie, H. M., 27, 34.
Hubbard, Gardiner Greene, 50.
Hunter, William, 9, 15, 19-23, 25, 33, 37.
Huntington, Collis Potter, 47.
Hurlbert, William Henry, 19-21, 26, 30-32, 38.
Hurlbut, George C., 51-53.
Iglesial, Ramon, 12.
Iglesias, José María, 22-25, 27 (ptd.), 36 (mentioned), 38 (mentioned).
International Railroad Co. of Texas see International and Great Northern Railroad Co.
International and Great Northern Railroad Co., 19-37, 44, 57, 62, 64, 86.
Isthmian canal, 45, 48, 52, 56, 57, 58, 62, 74.
Johnsen, Henry, 44.
Johnson, Andrew - Impeachment, 10-12.
Johnson, Lorenzo M., 51, 54.
Jones, J. O., 56.
Jones, Joseph Russell, 15, 16.
Juarez, Benito Pablo, 4 (mentioned), 7 (mentioned), 9, 21 (mentions death).
Kautz, August V., 14, 16.
Kennedy, John S., 29.
Kneass, Strickland, 1, 3.
Knight, Sarah N., 54, 55.
Kurass, Strickland d', 46.
Labastida y Davalos, Pelagio Antonio (archbishop of Mexico), 24.
Lancaster, Jones, Alfonso, 22.
La Remitrie, H. R. de, 10, 11.
Lastra y Bonillé, Luis N. de la, 11.
Lee, Albert Lindley, 19.
Lerdo de Tejada, Sebastián, 11-12, 14, 19, 21, 24, 30, 38, 39.
Lizardi, M. J. de, 12.
Lodge, Henry Cabot, 52.
Lopez, Felipe, 37.
Lord, C. H. 43.
McCook, Alexander, McDowell, 43.
McCook, Edward Moody, 23.
McCormick, Richard Cunningham, 11, 16, 19, 38-41, 43, 55.
McKinley, William, 50 (formal invitation, handwritten).
McLane, Allen, 9.
McLane, Robert Milligan, 33.
MacVeagh, (Isaac) Wayne, 52, 56.
Macin, F. D., 10, 27.
Mackie, Charles Paul, 36, 38, 39, 53.
Mackie, James S., 8, 13, 17, 34, 41, 42, 43, 54, 55.
Mackie, James Steuart, 42, 54, 56.
Madrid, Manuel I., 29, 30.
Magnus, R. von (Baron, Prussian minister to Mexico), 10.
Mancera, Gabriel, 19, 20.
Mariscal, Ignacio, 9, 14, 15, 23, 25, 33.
Marquand, Henry Gurdon, 22, 24, 25, 29, 30, 36, 37, 39, 41-43, 45.